<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paolo Chevalier</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Paolo Chevalier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Une approche spatio-temporelle de la dépendance à la mobilité dans les métropoles de Barcelone et d’Aix-Marseille-Provence</title>
      <link>/scientific-publications/thesedoctorat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scientific-publications/thesedoctorat/</guid>
      <description>Kind of scientific publication : PhD dissertation
Abstract (in french): Cette thèse tente d’éclairer un paradoxe entre, d’un côté, le fait que la mobilité spatiale constitue une ressource, notamment à l’accès à l’emploi ou au logement, et, de l’autre, que les pratiques de mobilité génèrent des coûts ou des difficultés importantes (en termes financiers, d’efforts au quotidien, de conséquences sur l’organisation de la vie personnelle ou familiale), en particulier pour ceux qui ont de longs budgets-temps de transport pour se rendre sur leur(s) lieu(x) de travail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diminution du nombre de logements disponibles pour les ménages et pression touristique, l’exemple de Barcelone</title>
      <link>/scientific-publications/articleteoros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scientific-publications/articleteoros/</guid>
      <description>Kind of scientific publication : Article in a scientific journal
Abstract: Ces dernières années, le tourisme augmente de manière exceptionnelle dans des villes européennes comme Barcelone. Simultanément à l’accroissement du nombre de visiteurs et celui des nuitées, le nombre de chambres disponibles dans l’hôtellerie traditionnelle progresse. Aussi, pour diversifier l’offre, la quantité de logements à usage touristique a augmenté. Cette forme d’hébergement touristique transforme progressivement le parc de logements dans les quartiers centraux de la ville, changement qui pourrait modifier la structure de la population résidente permanente.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Commutes, Another Dimension of Inequality among Low-Income Workers. Evidence from Barcelona and Marseille</title>
      <link>/scientific-publications/articlevieilla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scientific-publications/articlevieilla/</guid>
      <description>Kind of scientific publication : Chapter of a scientific book
Abstract: This article focuses on low-income workers who spend more than 90 minutes a day commuting between their place of residence and their workplace(s) in the metropolitan areas of Marseille and Barcelona. These workers typically require a longer commuting time per day than the rest of the population and, at the same time, they have limited economic resources to afford the said commute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essai</title>
      <link>/essai/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/essai/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>This is John
  Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>/essai/goisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/essai/goisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Hugo uses the excellent go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using go templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>/essai/hugoisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/essai/hugoisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Step 1. Install Hugo Goto hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your os and architecture.
Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.
More complete instructions are available at installing hugo
Step 2. Build the Docs Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.
Follow the following steps:
 Clone the hugo repository Go into the repo Run hugo in server mode and build the docs Open your browser to http://localhost:1313  Corresponding pseudo commands:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate from Jekyll</title>
      <link>/essai/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/essai/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Move static content to static Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png  should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png  Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>After studying in different European cities (Barcelona, Dublin, Lille, Paris, Rostock or Warsaw), I started a doctoral thesis under the joint supervision of Caroline Gallez (LVMT), Sandrine Wenglenski (LVMT) and Juan Antonio Módenes (CED) in October 2015. The 20th November 2020, I successfully defended my PhD dissertation A Spatial-Temporal Approach to the Dependence on Mobility in the metropolises of Barcelona and Aix-Marseille-Provence.
In January 2021, I began a new journey within the company Kisio in Lyon (France) where I continue my research agenda as well as working for a better understanding of GPS data in order to learn about individual daily mobility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data visualisation</title>
      <link>/data-visualisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-visualisation/</guid>
      <description>Maps Presenting the sample of my PhD research (place of residence and daily mobility)          Metropolis of Barcelona Metropolis of Marseille    Places of birth of the individuals from my sample
Comparing two metropolises          Road network and economic activity zones Distribution of the poverty rate    2D Spatio-temporal approach to daily mobility          Metropolis of Barcelona Metropolis of Marseille    2D Spatio-temporal approach to life courses               Graphs Observing the combination of means of transport and waiting time Comparing the distribution of a variable          Time Speed    Presenting the sample of my PhD research Presenting results of a logistic regression Presenting results of a multinomial logistic regression </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>Paolo Chevalier Born in Bordeaux (France), in July, 6th 1990. Driving license A1 and B
Experience  2021-Today Consultant in Data Science, Kisio (Lyon, France)   Analysing GPS data to better understand individual daily mobility   2015-Today Researcher, Laboratoire Ville Mobilité Transport (LVMT) (Champs-sur-Marne, France) and Centre d’Estudis Demogràfics (CED) (Barcelone, Espagne)   2020-Today: Research associate 2015-2020: PhD candidate   2017-2019 Teaching assistant, Université Paris-Est and École d’Urbanisme de Paris  (Champs-sur-Marne, France)   Teaching « Statistics and Cartography » to the 2nd year of Bachelor’s Degree in Geography Teaching « Demography » to the 1st year of Master’s Degree in Urban Planning   2017-2019 Reviewer,Documents d’Anàlisi Geogràfica (DAG) (Barcelona, Spain)   Reviewing scientific articles for the geographic review Documents d’Anàlisi Geogràfica (DAG)   2013 (2 months) Internship at the General Directorate of Planning, City Council of Bordeaux (Bordeaux, France)   Census of a new ecodistrict (Ginko, Bordeaux) Statistical analysis of its new inhabitants.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
